Siddharth Thakur

Delhi, India Mobile No: +91 9811608087

Github: https://github.com/siddharththakur26
Email ID: siddharththakur.26@gmail.com

Summary:

Over 4 years of IT experience on Quality Assurance particularly on Banking domain. Extensive Experience on developing various test artefacts. Hands on Experience on Test Management tools such as HP QC ALM, JIRA, Rational Clear Quest, SVN and Git. Familiarity with Agile processes, well Equipped with different kind of testing. Comprehensively worked on Web applications and have strong debugging skills. Strong Team player, enjoy learning and exploring new things and always look forward to reflect on mistakes.

Education:

- Master of Computing in AI and Software Engineering, Australian National University, Australia
- Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication, Amity University, India

Certification:

• ISQTB Foundation Level certified, 2018

Domain Knowledge:

Retail Banking
 Telecommunication
 Regulatory and Compliance

Technical Skills:

Test Artefacts : Requirement Traceability Matrix, Test Scenarios, Test

Cases, Bug Report, Test Plan

Test Management Tools : HP QC ALM, JIRA, SVN, Git, Rational Clear Quest

Testing: Functional, Smoke, Sanity, End to End, Component, Black

box, UI, Exploratory, Database testing

Agile Processes : Providing estimates of test scenarios, Reviews, Peers

evaluation/ walkthroughs/ inspection, Defect Triage calls, Scrum Meetings, Requirement meetings, Impact Analysis

Automation Tools : Selenium

Languages : Java, Python, SQL

Databases : Postgres, MYSQL, Oracle SQL

API Tools : SOAPUI, Postman

Operating System : Mac, Linux, Windows, Android

Performance tools : Jmeter

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IHS Markit, Guruqram India

Oct 2020 - Now

Associate I SQA Engineer

1. Project: Regulatory and Compliance (Product: KY3P, USA)

Oct 2020 - Now

Description: KY3P is an integrated suite of solutions to manage end-to-end third-party risk. Third-party relationships continue to under grow scrutiny by global regulators. As firms increase reliance on third parties to deliver business-critical processes and services, oversight complexity also increases.

Responsibilities:

- Designing functional test cases from functional specifications.
- Thorough testing of E2E flow of the Product features which includes Feed verifications.
- Designing Keyword based data driven Test framework and providing automation test cases reviews.
- Writing scripts for Functional test cases in Java for automation
- Writing jmeter scripts as per the SLA for non-functional requirements
- Evaluate third party API schema and response in the Postman and verify how it is stored in the database and displayed in Web app

Environment/Tools: Web application, Git, Selenium, Eclipse, Postman, Jmeter, Oracle SQL

Quality Assurance Engineering, Associate

2. Project: Core-Banking (Client: Community Bank, USA)

Mar 2016 – Feb 2017

Description: Fiserv provides comprehensive and integrated banking solutions. It provides integration environment and commitment to helps financial institutions gain significant efficiencies, better leverage the information in their enterprises and introduce new technology to their customers more quickly than ever.

Responsibilities:

- Prepared environment to test modules with new build versions. Sanity testing was done on such scenarios. Test data were prepared as a part of pre-conditions for test case execution.
- Developed the test plans for the testing different banking components such as Saving, Customers, Deposits etc. Performed all the backend the transactions that were required to test the components separately.
- Verified the defects by evaluating the behavior in the production and test environment. Provided the bug reports with proper screenshots of replicating the bugs so to re test those defects in order to pass the test cases.
- Tested the scenarios where the bank generates the reports for its batch transactions. Verified the logs generated by mainframe systems by running the batch processing commands in ISeries.
- Developed test cases to verify banking transactions and evaluate the transactions by checking the logs generated by the process.
- Prepared the Knowledge transfer notes for the team for all my test cases which had been executed so to quickly run such test cases during regression testing.
- Responsible for testing all the test cases of previous release in new test build versions as a part of regression.

Environment/Tools: Web application, HP QC ALM, SVN, Iseries

Virtusa, Bengaluru India

Jul 2013 – Feb 2016

Senior Engineer - QA

3. Project: BTWLMS (Client: British Telecom UK)

Jul 2013 - Feb 2016

Description: British Telecom White Labelled Managed Services (BTWLMS) that allows communications providers and other companies to offer their own branded national telephony and broadband products. It managed and maintained completely by BT Wholesale, leaving communications providers free to focus on the sales and marketing of products.

Responsibilities:

- Worked as System Integration tester.
- Analyzed the Business requirement to design the high level and low level test basis. Developed requirement traceability matrix documents to their respective test scenarios, test cases and all the defects.
- Validated Web API responses with the help of SOAP UI. A certain XML payload is sent to API through Putty and Validated with invalid and valid payloads.
- Raised defects to corresponding test cases which are used to caught while testing the web application. All the
 raised defects were used to block the test cases with their level of priority set by me.
- Prepared Test data for the testing purposes so to test it at different test environments. Use of MySQL to modify
 the test data according to test cases for the preparing specific test data.
- Develop Test Strategy Plan to note down the effective ways of executing the test cases and provide Knowledge transfer session to the User Acceptance Test teams and to the new joiners.

Environment/Tools: Web Application, HP QC ALM, JIRA, SOAP UI, XML

FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

Open Up, Cape Town South Africa (Remote)

Jul 2020 – Oct 2020

QA - Freelancer

4. Project: Wazimap (Client: Open Up)

Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

Description: Wazimap, from the Xhosa word ulwazi for knowledge, provides easy access to South African census and elections data. This includes election results from 2011, 2014 and 2016; racial, income, education, unemployment and access to basic services down to ward level.

Responsibilities:

- Going through the Requirement document to design the workflow for end to end test scenarios.
- Developing User acceptance to validate the web application which allow to improve the test coverage.
- Implemented a POC to automate functional testing with help of Selenium web driver, Python and Behave framework.
- Implemented parallel test execution using Docker and used Travis for build process management.

Environment/Tools: Linux, Selenium web driver, Python, POM, behave.

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Feb 2019 - May 2019

Australia National University, Canberra, Australia

Student

5. Project: COMP8100: Requirement Elicitation and Analysis techniques.

Feb 2019 - May 2019

Description: The course is eliciting, describing and managing requirements during the early period of systems and software development. Several analysis techniques and requirements Models are studied among with the various modelling methods.

Responsibilities:

- Implement the methods to set priorities and severities of the stakeholder's requirements.
- Developed Non-functional Quality attributes of Software Requirement Specification
- Worked on the one of the case study on the Hotel Management Booking System to extract test cases from the requirements.
- Used Class diagram and Data Diagram to extract feature map and further broken down to test scenarios

6. Project: COMP8110: Managing Software Projects in a System Context

Feb 2019 – May 2019

Description: The course's principles of software project management that support a project manager to carry out the project administrative functions of a program office, lead and manage an agile project development team.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in designing and building Epics, stories and tasks.
- Developed to provide measure on estimates by developing story points for every particular task.
- Optimize and improve the process of walkthrough and inspections by working on the research reports as a part
 of the case study.